(GIRL SCREAMING IN FILM)
(GIRL SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING) Help!
(SCREAMING)
Help! Somebody!
Ripped and released by sharpysword(SCREAMING)
(AUDIENCE SCREAMING)
(DIALING PHONE)
(GIRL IN FILM SCREAMING)
(GIRLS GIGGLING)
That scared the
living crap out
of me.
Meryl Streep
that girl was not.
Who's Meryl Streep?
Oh, Zoe, she's like
Katie Holmes to our
parents, okay?
So, what's next,
ladies?
I have to go home.
No.
Yeah, make that
a block from home.
I can't
have another close
encounter with my parents.
They think
I'm home in bed.
DAVE:
Were you kids in bed
at a reasonable hour?
I stayed up till 10:00.
After 9:00,
Rhett was fast asleep.
DAVE:
Who's driving
these monsters?
I will. Nicki's selling coffee
at school and I promised
I'd help her.
Hmm.
I know, it sucks.
Do not say "sucks."
Say "disappoints"
or "bites."
I don't need a lunch. I can
walk across the street with
Tash.
And have pizza three
days in a row?
I think not.
That's really good.
The proportions
are perfect,
but are you drawing
what you're really
seeing?
The simplest thing
is the hardest.
To see what's really
right in front of you.
Hey,
so what mad fun
is on for tonight?
Oh, I am
so grounded.
I got busted by my 'rents
sneaking back inside
last night.
Damn, girl,
how'd you manage that?
My dad set the
motion detector.
It seems like our parents are
getting paranoid about us
in their old age.
Mine still trust me.
(ALL LAUGHING)
GRACE: It's beautiful.
Well, it hasn't
been a bad couple of
decades, considering.
For me?
Better than the
first two without you.
To 20 years of you and me.
And to
our children,
safe at home.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(WHOOPING)
(ALL CHEERING)
Cool, you lost them!
Totally macho
Mustang boys, too boot.
(WHOOPING)
Boo-yah! We struck
a blow for sisterhood.
That's
the only "blow"
you know, sister.
Diss.
(GIRLS OOHING)
So what's the rave
scene this weekend?
Full Moon Underground.
I've been hearing
San Bernardino.
Probably Saturday.
I'm gonna tell
my mom I'm staying over
at your house, okay, Tash?
I cannot believe you can
still work that old scam.
What can I say? My 'rents
are just adorably clueless.
(GIRLS GIGGLING)
So, I'll bring the glowsticks
if somebody else buys the gas.
TASH: Oh, that's such
a good idea. Nice try,
beams.
Rest up, it's gonna be
one hell of a weekend.
Bye, Tasha.
Don't let
the bedbugs bite.
Hasta.
All right.
(SCOFFS)
Now they call
the cops on me.
(VOICES CHATTERING
ON POLICE RADIO)
Hello?
I'm sorry I'm late.
Ruby Baker?
Yeah, I'm Ruby.
And, you know, whatever
they said, I'm not missing.
I just went out.
Your parents were
in a car accident.
Are they okay?
Ruby,
why don't you
have a seat, hon?
Are they okay?
My partner's gonna
help you to have
a seat.
Ruby.
I can sit down myself!
I understand.
I said, are they okay?
Relax. I need you to relax.
Why won't you answer me?
We're here to help you.
You're gonna be okay.
Relax.
Ruby?
Ruby! Ruby!
OFFICER 1: She will be okay.
Get her pulse.
OFFICER 2: Can
you hear me, Ruby?
MINISTER: They are as asleep.
In the morning they are
like grass which groweth up.
In the morning,
it flourisheth
and groweth up.
In the evening,
it is cut down
and withereth.
For we
are consumed
by thine anger,
and
by thy wrath
are we troubled.
Thou hast set our
iniquities before
thee,
our secret sins in the
light of thy countenance.
For all our days
are passed away
in thy wrath.
We spend our years
as a tale that is told,
so teach us to
number our days.
So that we may apply
our hearts into wisdom.
I think Rhett Baker wants
to come up and say something.
Rhett?
(STAMMERING) I just...
I...
(VOICE BREAKING)
I just wanna say...
I...
I just...
It's okay.
I didn't work
with Dave and Grace
or see them every day,
but I knew them
both for ten years,
and I'm sure if they
could hear all this...
Well, Grace would do her
dismissive little giggle.
You know the one.
And Dave would mutter
an expletive deleted.
(CROWD CHUCKLES)
They would just hate to be
remembered as anything
but ordinary.
Which
is exactly
what they were.
Anything but ordinary.
But they will live on
through their children
and in all our hearts.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Ruby?
Do you remember me?
I'm
your Uncle Jack,
your mom's brother.
I'll go wait
by the car,
okay?
Look, I just want
you to know if there's
anything that you need,
anything I can do...
I don't mean in the next
few weeks or months,
I mean anytime.
How come I haven't seen you
in, like, I don't know,
ten years?
Have you even met
my brother Rhett?
Of course I have.
I haven't seen either
of you in years,
but,
first of all, I live
pretty far away, in
Chicago.
Then
how are you
gonna help us?
I don't know.
There's the phone,
there's e-mail.
You
and my mom never did
write each other though.
That's true.
You know, Ruby, as siblings
get older, sometimes they
go their separate ways.
I know
you and Rhett
are close now.
No, we're not.
Discounting DNA,
we have nothing
in common.
I used to feel
that way about
your mom.
It's not true.
I used to think that
when things slowed down,
I'd
take a month off
and come out here,
and
get to know you
and your brother
and Grace again.
It's nice to see you again.
I'm sorry things didn't
work out.
I'll call you later, okay?
Okay.
Ruby?
Hi.
I'm Alvin Begleiter.
I'm so sorry.
I'm your...
Was
your parents'
estate lawyer.
I helped them
plan their wills,
what it is that they wanted
to do with their money
and...
Well, actually the most
important issue right now,
is who's going to be
taking care of you.
You and Rhett.
I'm assuming
that you know
the Glasses, correct?
They were
my next-door neighbors.
I've known them my whole life.
That's good, because I
know that your parents
chose them after
a great deal of
consideration.
You know,
there's something else.
Your parents were
extremely thrifty,
and with
your mom's share
of the inheritance,
your dad's life insurance,
there's more than
enough for you and Rhett
for the rest of your lives.
Well, then, obviously
you don't know Rhett.
That's good.
I like that.
I'm gonna
give you one of my cards.
I don't expect any trouble.
But
if you have
any concerns,
any problems,
I'm an estate lawyer, but
I'm also what they call
a trust lawyer.
And I wanna be someone
you can trust.
You call me, okay?
Okay.
BEGLEITER:
Mr. Glass.
Ruby.
Thank you.
My mom
and dad would have
really loved that speech.
They would
have loved it.
Come here.
That's good.
We're gonna
get through this.
get through it
together, okay?
(SIGHING)
Oh, Ruby.
You're in good hands.
Hey!
You guys ready for Malibu?
It'll be
a big change,
we won't lie.
TERRY: But it's not
the worst place either.
RHETT: Cool!
Is this your car?
You in there already?
My company's,
on loan for today.
RHETT: Sweet.
This place is huge.
Hey, Rubes,
check out this view.
RUBY: Yeah,
it's pretty amazing.
Cool!
A meteorite.
It's art.
It's art, Rhett.
Terry,
give them
the grand tour.
Stall them while
I order some dinner.
Let's
get the lay
of the land.
So, master suite.
Home gym.
Home theater.
Sweet.
It's
like you never
have to leave home.
Oh, if only.
This is Vicki.
She comes in
most days.
(BOTH SPEAKING SPANISH)
Hello.
This is your room.
It's just temporary
quarters, of course.
Well,
you unpack,
get settled,
and
I'll meet you
in the kitchen.
We're sharing a room?
If you even glance
at me when I'm changing
for bed, you are so busted.
Okay, we have
a little calamari,
we have
a little risotto with
portabella mushrooms. Mmm!
And
a little green salad
with some Swiss chard.
Do you have any Garfield?
What is that?
It's crap in a can.
If it's crap,
how come you
eat it?
Come on, kids.
Try the calamari.
Isn't that squid?
(CHUCKLES IMPATIENTLY)
Honey, tonight...
I'll call Domino's.
Thank you.
(RHETT MAKING BEEPING NOISES)
(SCREECHING)
Can't
you just turn
and face the wall?
Who are you,
the Blair Witch?
No, I'm worse.
Can you just face
the goddamn wall?
Turn that stupid thing off.
ERIN: Honey,
there's public school, and
then there's public school.
Trust me, there won't
be any Bloods or Crips.
I'm not scared of
getting gunned down.
Ruby,
you're a great kid.
You're gonna have...
It's not about being great
or not great. It's about
being...
New?
Middle-of-the-year new.
Look, there's a little saying
that we teach to the patients
in the pain ward.
This too shall pass.
(BELL RINGING)
(STUDENTS CHATTERING)
Hi. Why don't you just
take a seat in the back?
We have a new addition.
Would you introduce
yourself, Miss Baker?
You just did.
Hi.
I'm Ruby Baker.
I used
to go to Shady Lane.
That's in the Valley.
That's not my choice, it
was just an accident of
birth.
(STUDENTS CHUCKLING)
So how come you
moved here now?
That's another accident.
Let's all make Ruby
feel welcome.
Thanks for the lift,
Vicki.
Sweet!
I can't believe it.
I can't believe it!
Neither can I.
Like one of those isn't
noisy and obnoxious enough.
No, Rubes,
because you can't play
Pokemon Snap on Playstation.
But you
can play Ape Escape,
but you can't on N-64.
Mom and Dad would
totally just freak out.
Don't talk about Mom and Dad.
(PLAYSTATION BEEPING)
(VIDEO GAME MUSIC PLAYING)
RUBY:
I haven't even seen, like,
one girl with blue-black hair.
And all the
guys spend all day
surfing and swimming,
that whole bizarre physical
culture of sun-worshipping.
Well,
that sounds fairly hot.
So, anyway, I was crazy
checking my pager all day,
'cause I figured
you'd call, and
you didn't.
I was just dying to call you
at lunch but the cell phones
are banned at the school.
And,
like, the kids
just don't care.
You know, they just
can't see that they've
lost their civil liberties.
Probably
'cause they have
so much sunstroke,
they're, like,
permanently wasted.
ERIN: Ruby?
I got us an assortment
of different things
this time.
Some cold pastas,
some salads.
Ruby, I really think that you
would be well served by
a better attitude.
It's...
It's okay.
I don't mind take-out.
I know that you guys are busy.
It's not like it's from
Wendy's or anything.
I'm speaking
about your attitude
toward your new school.
My attitude?
I overheard
your conversation.
You were listening in
on my call?
No, I was trying to get
a line out, but that's
beside the point.
The point is, you need
those kids to like you.
Otherwise you're just going to
isolate yourself, sabotage
yourself.
You're
going to have
a miserable time.
Okay, I get it.
I learned something.
GRACE: Ruby?
Ruby.
Wake up.
I'm awake.
Mommy?
(GASPING)
My God, you scared
the crap out of me.
Well, I heard noises.
I thought it was
a burglar or
a coyote.
I'm not used to having kids
in the house.
Come here.
Thank you.
You gotta be freezing.
So no more 3:00 a.m. swims,
okay?
With all the glass,
you can hear everything.
I gotta
start setting
the alarm at night.
Are you coming?
MAN:
Though drunk-driving
among California teens
has been
steadily decreasing,
we can still do better.
As these images
starkly attest,
alcohol remains the number one
drug problem among young
people today.
This year,
more than 20%
of teenage drivers...
(LAUGHING)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(SCREECHING)
So, how was
your first day
of driver's ed?
Fine, I guess.
They still show
those gruesome
movies?
Honey,
those were
the dark ages.
I'm sure they have more
enlightened ways of teaching
kids today, don't they?
May I be excused?
Stupid kid-proof
piece of crap.
Ruby?
Was it awful?
I mean,
the driving class?
I can just imagine.
No, it's...
I have my period.
Oh.
Well, come with me.
Thank you.
Four out of five
doctors recommend.
This cramp,
too, shall pass.
(ENGINE REVVING)
I'll turn it off
just as soon as I
get to a safe point.
(SLURRING) It's cool.
I don't care.
It's kind of relaxing.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROANING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
TERRY: (THROUGH WALL)
Erin! Get out of there!
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
What were you doing in the
bathroom? Tell me the truth!
ERIN: What
are you implying
with that question?
You tell me.
No, I'm not going
to answer you.
Good night.
What the hell
were you doing?
Getting ready for bed.
I'm tired.
Watch your language.
There's kids in
the house.
Don't play games
with me, Erin.
Don't play games with me.
You know exactly what
I'm talking about.
I'm too
tired to even guess
what you're picking at.
I am sick of
your accusations.
Tired?
Is that what
you call it now?
How many times
have I asked...
I've done everything
you've asked me to do.
(SHOUTING)
So help me...
Ruby?
Hi, I'm Hannah.
Hi.
So, there's this rumor you
were on academic probation
at your old school.
Cut to the chase, huh?
(CHUCKLES)
I was, and then I had sex
with the dean of students,
and he took it off my record.
Oh, not really.
(LAUGHS)
I was supposed to
be at my friend Tasha's
house one Saturday night
doing an essay
on the Yalta conference,
and went to this rave instead.
Come Sunday, I was totally
fried and downloaded this
thing off the Net.
Tuesday, I was busted.
Hannah!
Hey!
I gotta go.
Bye.
Hey,
what are you doing?
Hey, Ruby.
There's a premiere
in Westwood,
and my
company's driving
a bunch of people.
I gotta stop by and make sure
everything's running smooth.
You wanna come?
Well, I have homework tonight.
Probably three more hours.
Pretty heavy, so...
That's perfect.
So, are we going to catch the
tail end of the movie or go
straight to the party?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Actually,
the hell with Westwood.
If my drivers can't
handle a lousy premiere...
VALET:
Evening, sir.
Mud pie for the lady,
Ketel One, rocks,
for me.
Great.
Thank you.
That party'd
be a mob scene.
What I really want
to do is talk to you.
WAITRESS: Here you are.
TERRY: Thank you.
I remember
when you guys
moved down the block,
what, 11 years ago?
It was funny.
I noticed
the furniture as
they brought it in.
Erin noticed
there was a little girl.
But you were upset.
I guess about
moving cross-country.
You wouldn't say a word.
Just
hugged this plastic doll
against your little chest.
Malibu Barbie,
I think it was.
Prophetic, huh?
I think you
mean "pathetic."
(LAUGHING)
No, no, no.
I guess you moved on
years ago.
From what?
From hugging plastic dolls.
I should hope so.
Last night,
when you two
were fighting,
it had nothing to
do with us, right?
No, no, no, no, no.
Married people
sometimes like to
push
each other's buttons
just because they can.
It's another form of intimacy.
A lower form, but nothing
serious.
There's
one thing I haven't
told you about Erin.
It
can be lonely
living with her.
But that's my cross to bear.
Not yours.
I think it's past
my bedtime, Terry.
Of course it is.
Let's get you to bed.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORNS HONKING)
Terry.
You're not wearing
your shoulder belt.
Hey. Try not to
make too much noise.
I'm sure Rhett
and Erin are asleep.
Okay?
Hamlet senses something's
wrong right under his nose,
that he alone
can set right.
I want two pages next
Friday on what he means,
and whether he succeeds.
(BELL RINGING)
Mr. Begleiter,
before my parents...
Um...
Did they ever talk to
you about finding different
guardians for Rhett and me?
Different
from the Glasses?
Mmm-mmm.
Well, I think
that they wanted to.
They
talked about
that with you?
No.
But my parents weren't nearly
as friendly with them after
they moved.
Well,
Ruby, the Glasses
aren't your parents.
They're never
gonna be your
parents.
But
if Erin or Terry
has done anything...
We sleep in one room,
Rhett and me.
Well, that's not ideal.
And then, the other night,
we were alone in Terry's
car, and he...
What? What'd he do?
He just put
my seat belt on.
But the way
he leaned across me,
it wasn't... It just...
And I felt...
I know it sounds stupid.
But...
And then I walked in
and Erin was shooting up.
I saw her
holding a needle.
Anyway,
she looked
really baked.
Ruby.
Ruby, try and
understand this.
The accident, in effect,
orphaned you
and your brother.
So, if this doesn't
work out with the
Glasses,
you have no place to go.
You're gonna become
wards of the state.
And I'm not trying
to scare you.
I'm just
telling you
the facts of life.
I drove halfway here
from Malibu with the
housekeeper,
and then I hitchhiked the rest
of the way, and I was really
scared.
But I kept telling myself,
once I made it, you'd
help me and Rhett.
When we met,
you said you were
somebody I could trust.
Okay.
All right.
I believe you,
and I know who to
get in touch with.
It's not gonna be easy.
I can't promise you
any results.
But I can promise you
that I will look into
this.
You have my word on that.
Thank you.
When we spoke
after the funeral...
Mmm-hmm?
Uh...
You had said that...
We had more than
enough.
Mmm-hmm.
How much would that be,
exactly?
Well, that's
really a question
for the trust officer
over at the
LA Federal Bank.
But between us?
Four million dollars.
So you can see, you're
financially very secure.
Yeah.
Now why don't
you run on home and
do me one more favor?
No hitchhiking.
This is out, okay?
Yes, sir.
Yeah,
Alvin Begleiter calling.
I just
had a real disturbing
visit from Ruby Baker.
Rhett,
why don't you
leave that now?
Go and do some homework.
RUBY: I have a bunch
of homework to do, too.
Stay a minute, would you?
TERRY: What you walked
in on last night isn't
what you think.
Erin suffers
from diabetes.
I've kept that private.
It's not something I want
to worry you or Rhett about.
The disease
is under control.
So what you
saw last night
was
Erin giving herself her
nightly insulin injection.
It must've
been a shock
to walk in on.
One more thing.
Terry tells me that...
You got
a little skittish
with him last night.
That makes us feel sad.
We want you to
trust us, Ruby.
We need your trust.
I know I overreacted.
I'm sorry.
There are still some things
that I need to get used to
around here.
We all do.
We're all under stress.
I'm
gonna go begin
my Hamlet paper.
Well, hey,
if you need any
help, let me know.
That'd be great.
That's fine,
and now you're gonna
put the car in park...
And step out.
Mmm-hmm.
And Ruby,
you're going to get
behind the wheel next.
You can apply
a little more
gas, Ruby.
(ENGINE ACCELERATING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
I'm sorry,
I'm a real
bad driver.
There aren't
any bad drivers,
just inexperienced ones.
Now take a breath, Ruby.
Let's start driving
back again.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
SECRETARY: No, Mr. Robinson,
I'm sorry, he's not in
right now,
but I'll have him call
you back as soon as
he can.
Hi. Uh...
I'm Ruby Baker.
I'm, uh, Terry's...
I know who you are, Ruby.
Okay, cool.
Uh...
I stopped by
to catch a ride home
from Terry when he's ready.
He's having a powwow
with some people right now,
but if you want to wait,
there's a really nice
lounge behind me.
(PHONE RINGING)
Okay, thank you.
SECRETARY:
Glass Transit.
How may I help you?
MAN ON PA: Any available
service technician,
please come to the office.
SECRETARY: May I have
the phone number please?
Okay,
is he arriving
at 8:00 p.m...
MAN: So, what's
going on, Terry?
TERRY: Oh, the usual.
But not to worry, fellas.
It's nothing that can't
be handled.
Mr. Glass,
we had a payment plan.
The dates arrive,
the money doesn't.
TERRY:
About that payment plan,
in the cold light of day,
I would have to
call it unrealistic.
You proposed that plan.
Yeah, I know. I know.
It's not dishonesty.
You gotta give me that.
What is it, Terry,
if not dishonesty?
Naive optimism.
(MAN LAUGHING)
But then again, I'm
an optimist by nature.
That's how I
succeed in business,
by betting on myself.
I'll be right with you.
(MUFFLED CONVERSATION)
MAN: Where is the money
we loaned you, Mr. Glass?
TERRY: You're
not listening.
The money will be...
(GRUNTS)
Don't say "will be," always
say "is," as in "the money
is..."
Yeah.
Can I help you?
Whose car is this?
Hell if I know.
Just showed up
one day.
One day when?
Uh, I don't know,
a few months ago.
We used
to have a car
kind of like this.
You know, you really
shouldn't be back here.
TERRY: Ruby!
Ruby!
What happened
before was nothing. It
was just a business glitch.
Hope
you didn't
get freaked.
People get very weird
about money.
I didn't mean to, uh,
just show up like that.
You know,
I waited for Vicki,
and she never came.
Yeah,
we had to
let Vicki go.
Erin was coming for you,
but she got held up at
the hospital.
Wait, back up. You
had to let Vicki go?
Yeah, we had to.
She drove you somewhere
without anyone's permission.
Just to Santa Monica,
to the promenade, to
hang out with some kids.
Mmm-hmm.
How
did you know
that she drove me?
(CHUCKLING)
How did we know?
It's our job to know.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Did
you have a hard
day at work, Erin?
Oh, it was fine,
Ruby, thank you.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(CHUCKLING) Hamlet.
Don't you hate how
he can't make up
his mind?
Mmm-hmm.
To be, not be, not,
not be, be, be, not.
(TERRY LAUGHING)
(GASPING)
My father drove a Saab.
(GROANING)
Terry!
Thank you.
You know,
finishing my paper.
Ah, that would be wrong.
(CHATTERING)
Ruby?
Yeah?
Would you mind
coming with me?
Sure.
NANCY: Ruby Baker?
I'm Nancy Ryan.
I'm an inspector with the
Department of Social Services.
Your estate lawyer let us
know that you may have some
problems with your guardians.
Is that right?
Ruby, please relax
and be open with me.
Everything said here
stays private, okay?
So,
you're 16, and
your brother
is 11.
And
you're currently
sharing a bedroom.
Yeah, for now.
And,
you saw Erin Glass
injecting herself?
They said
she has diabetes.
Diabetes?
Okay, I'm gonna
double-check that.
You're
writing down
everything I say,
so that
now it's gonna
be in writing twice.
My word's still not
gonna count for shit
next to Terry Glass
and Dr. Glass, right?
Which is why,
when we're done, I'm
gonna phone the Glasses
and ask them to meet me at
their home so that I can
verify everything
with my own eyes.
Okay?
But...
Then how am I gonna live
with them if they know
that I told on 'em?
Do you want to live with them?
Sometimes things are fine.
Last night,
Terry helped
me with something,
but maybe that was just to
keep me happy, keep my
mouth shut.
I know
this is scary for you,
but you don't have to worry.
In
a situation like this,
we tell the guardians
that we're performing
a routine site inspection.
If it's
still in progress
when you get home,
you just act like
we've never met
or spoken.
You have no idea
why I'm there.
Okay?
Ms. Ryan, this is my
husband, Terry Glass.
Hello.
Is this really necessary in
the middle of a business day?
I mean,
15 minutes notice?
We're gonna get this done
as quickly as possible,
Mr. Glass.
Feels
like an intrusion.
Let's get it over with.
May I...
TERRY: Of course.
It looks like only
one child sleeps
in here.
Yes, Rhett.
Rhett, yes.
And the girl, Ruby,
she has her own room?
Of course.
She's 16.
Nice accommodations.
(CHATTERING)
I think the kids are home.
Would you like to meet them?
Yes, I would.
Just to say hi.
Oh, but
first, Dr. Glass,
may I look upstairs?
I know this is awkward,
but it's also important.
It's a matter of child safety,
just ensuring there's nothing
dangerous
in easy reach
of an 11-year-old.
"Humulin L and U."
Diabetes.
I'm type one,
insulin dependent.
And we have it totally
under control.
It would appear that you do.
There's the two
best kids in
the world.
Hi. You
must be Rhett.
I'm Nancy Ryan.
Nice to meet you.
NANCY: Nice to meet you.
So,
Rhett, how do you
spend your evenings?
Well, when I finish
my homework, I read.
And you must be Ruby.
You have a very nice
room.
Sorry for the
inconvenience.
You've made
a wonderful home
for these children.
Thank you, Dr. Glass.
Thank you.
NANCY: Oh.
ERIN: We'll see you out.
(CONVERSATION CONTINUES)
You read?
You lie.
Guess who I learned from?
Good-bye now.
(CHATTERING)
Why
don't we order
some dinner, hon?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
So, how do you
like your new room?
It couldn't have
come at a better
time.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(ELECTRONIC WARBLING)
Come on, Mr. Begleiter.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
MAN: So sorry to disturb
you at your home at this
late hour.
But I found myself wide awake
and wondering, "Where's the
money?"
TERRY: Well, you might as
well know. Six months ago,
I took on a partner,
a silent partner. And,
it just recently
came to my attention
that the little son of
a bitch was skimming cash.
MAN: You lost me.
What does this all have
to do with our little loan?
I'm waiting, Mr. Glass.
Mr. Glass,
you still there?
Yeah.
TERRY: He was charging
a whole host of personal
expenses to the company.
Guess what, Terry.
Whenever I want to hear
a heartbreaking human
interest story,
I can watch
the local news.
Meanwhile, your next payment
is due tomorrow, close of
business.
Do you fully understand me,
Mr. Glass?
Yeah, I'm here.
And I'm seeking full
restitution from my
silent partner.
Plus,
I found a whole
new source of equity.
My big, new
personal piggy bank.
So you can expect another
30 grand from me right
off the bat.
That barely covers
the interest.
You need to start paying
off the principal,
my friend.
Of course, but the point is
that I need some more time.
Not a lot more time.
A week at the most.
A week at the most?
We'll give you two days,
as a favor, because we
like you,
and because
we'd hate for you to
come home tomorrow night
and find your beautiful house
burned down with your wife
inside.
(HANGS UP)
(REDIAL BEEPING)
(LINE RINGING)
MAN: Yeah?
"I could a tale unfold whose
lightest word would harrow
up thy soul,
"freeze thy young blood,
"make
thy two eyes, like stars,
start from their spheres
"and each particular
hair to stand on end.
"If thou didst ever
thy dear father love,
"revenge his foul and
most unnatural murder.
"Murder most foul...
"But this most foul,
strange, and unnatural."
WOMAN: Begleiter,
Tepper and Brice.
Hello, this is Ruby Baker
for Mr. Begleiter, please.
One moment, please.
BEGLEITER: Hello, Ruby.
Did you get my e-mail?
No, 'cause
Terry trashed
my AOL account.
Or maybe
the bill just didn't get paid
in the confusion of your move.
Whatever. Did you
find out about
the BMW?
Right, the BMW.
Yeah,
it was registered
to a business, G.T.I.
Glass Transit, Incorporated.
Terry's company.
So now don't you get it?
Ruby, please
come with me.
I think I have to
call you back later.
Bye-bye.
This is
Miss Bassett,
our vice principal.
Ruby, the paper
that you turned
in to Mr. Kim,
that was your work,
nobody helped you?
No.
Not even Harold Bloom?
The phrase "Hamlet's
dance of contraries"
didn't sound like
one of my students.
I found it and other
sentences and phrases
in Mr. Bloom's recent book,
Shakespeare:
The Invention Of The Human.
We were told there's already
one case of plagiarism on
your school record.
Do you understand why we have
to take decisive action in
a situation like this?
You were told?
By who?
That is
hardly the issue
here, young lady.
This sort
of cheating has to
have real consequences.
We've
already spoken
to your guardians.
Of course you have.
And frankly, we're not sure
whether you can continue
at this school.
Well?
Why don't you ask Terry?
Or maybe it's
time you started taking some
personal responsibility, Ruby.
Yeah, maybe it's time.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(LINE RINGING)
JACK ON ANSWERING MACHINE:
Hi, you've reached Jack Avery.
I'm out of the country, but
I'll be checking my machine
occasionally,
so leave a message.
(CREAKING)
(GASPING)
Come on, Rhett. Wake up.
Oh...
Shh, don't make a sound, okay?
I'm gonna get you dressed.
We're gonna go.
Where? With who?
Away with me.
Hey, quit it.
You're looking.
Right,
like there's
something to see.
It's raining.
I was sleeping.
I don't wanna go.
Yes, you do, it's
gonna be really fun.
They're giving away free
Dragon Ball Z tapes at
Blockbuster
and we can get in line
real early and avoid
the rush.
Really?
Whoa!
Close the door.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
What if they find out?
I'll take
the blame, okay?
Just get in the car.
(ENGINE STARTING)
You
don't know what
you're doing, huh?
You wanna slow down
a little?
One thing I learned
from Terry, buckle up.
Whoa!
Rubes, Terry's
gonna kill you!
Maybe so.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Turn that off.
Turn that shit off!
(HORN HONKING)
RHETT: Look out!
You almost
creamed that guy.
That's right.
Now turn it off!
(MUSIC STOPS)
I wanna go back.
We're not going back.
What do you mean,
"We're not going
back"?
That's what I said, genius.
Figure it out.
We have to go back! You
tricked me into this, and
now I'm gonna get in trouble.
No, they tricked you,
the Glasses.
What do you mean?
Did not. They were sleeping.
(CAR HORN HONKING)
What I mean is they were gonna
send me away to the middle
of goddamn nowhere,
so I couldn't be any
more trouble, and you'd just
stay home with Terry and Erin.
I like Terry. I like Erin.
No, you like all
the shiny shit that
they blinded you with,
so you couldn't see what
was right under your nose.
They made you lie
to that social worker.
She could've helped us.
I didn't know that she was
a social worker, okay?
All I knew was...
That you didn't want
to be separated from
your beloved Nintendo.
They bought you off.
Where are you taking us?
I don't know yet.
The point was just
to get away.
RUBY: Crap.
Just don't say
anything stupid.
The
highway is closed
from here to Sunset.
There's a mud slide.
You're gonna have to
use Malibu Canyon or...
Can I see
your driver's
license, Miss?
My driver's license?
And your registration, too,
please.
It's over there
in all of my stuff.
I think I saw it over here.
I'm gonna
have to ask you to
pull onto the shoulder
and step out
of the car,
please.
TERRY: Officer!
These are my kids.
Terry Glass,
Glass Transit.
The limos we loaned you
for last year's parade?
Oh, yeah!
OFFICER: How are you?
(CONVERSATION CONTINUES)
Rhett, you poor baby,
come with me. It's okay.
We have a little
behavioral problem
back at the old homestead.
She's going through a really
hard time right now,
sweetheart.
ERIN: God only knows
what's going on in
her mind.
TERRY:
Well, you know,
teenage girl stuff.
Gotcha. Good luck.
Move over, hon.
You can turn
around right here.
Thanks.
Don't you have anything
to say to me?
You killed my parents.
That's not just insane,
it's hurtful.
You were
obviously threatened by
your business associates.
I saw it.
Like Erin
said to me the other day,
"We need your trust, Ruby."
You need my trust, for sure.
Four million dollars' worth.
I got a thriving business.
My wife is a successful
doctor.
I got a big, new...
New personal piggy bank!
That's just words
out of context.
Just words.
What about your BMW
my dad was driving
that night?
And what about it?
For your
parents' anniversary,
I lent them a beamer
so Dave wouldn't have to drive
Grace around in that dinky old
Saab,
which I hammered
out and repainted.
No good deed
goes unpunished, huh?
Because in your
trashy teenage mind,
you twisted that into...
What do you think? I what?
Cut the steering linkage?
Stripped the brakes?
Yeah.
It's understandable. It's
basic psychology, you know?
'Cause
you don't wanna blame
your dad for what happened.
The fact
that he had too much
booze in him that night.
Then you'd have to ask
yourself why your mom
and dad
were hitting
the bottle so hard.
Whose bad behavior
had driven them to
drink?
Get this straight, Ruby.
You and Rhett are mine.
Now I suggest you forget your
lurid, adolescent female
fantasies and start...
(SCREAMS)
Help! Help!
Let go, you bastard!
Better calm down, little girl.
Help!
Ow!
What's happening out there?
Your sister is having
a tantrum, honey.
Come on.
Come back to bed.
No! Let me go!
Get off!
Let go!
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING) Now
listen hard, Ruby.
Anything happens to you,
we got Rhett for seven
more years
and all we need is
one surviving child.
Erin!
Erin, stop him, please!
Please!
Erin!
Erin, please come help me.
Please!
He's not gonna hurt you,
I promise. Please!
Shh.
No! Erin, please,
no! Erin, no! No!
(SPITS)
Thank you for being
such a good listener.
ERIN: You'll feel better now,
Ruby.
Rest, relax.
Now where to, ladies?
I vote the mall.
Hey, wait, timeout.
Has anyone heard
from Ruby?
Me? Not for a month.
Same. Won't even
answer my e-mails.
What up with
Little Miss Malibu?
Too busy bodysurfing
for her old gal pals?
Well,
then, we are
too busy for her.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
MAN: Where is the rest
of our money, Mr. Glass?
You're just not
gonna believe this.
The bank mailed me a check,
but with the wrong zip code.
Some incompetent jerk
at the bank inverted
the last two digits.
So basically I
will need another...
(HANGS UP)
WOMAN: Next in line.
(CHATTERING)
We gotta
expand the house.
A wing for the kids.
Sir.
Our little boy is getting
bigger and bigger every day.
Of course, the girl's a teen.
I don't know if you've got
any kids of your own...
Anyway, construction costs
in Malibu are off the charts,
and I'm estimating
a quarter million,
minimum.
Well, we'll need to
see blueprints, Mr. Glass.
There's an approval process.
Well, you
can't get blueprints
without an architect,
and my architect is looking
for cash down payment.
He's in demand.
I believe
we advanced you
$30,000 for
that purpose
just last month.
But that was for a room,
Ted.
Before
I realized
I needed a wing.
And isn't it a general
principle of a guardianship
to keep the
children comfortable?
Here's the trust document.
It authorizes me
to use trust money
to enlarge the house.
And isn't it also
a general principle
that the guardians aren't
supposed to suffer
economically
in the fulfillment
of their obligations?
TED: Mr. Glass...
I'm paying
two tuitions at
the Westcott School.
I'm employing
a full-time nanny.
These kids are seeing
top therapists to help
them deal with a tragedy.
I'm planning family trips
to broaden their horizons,
and it's like a root canal
every time I need
reimbursement.
Where did you get that?
I thought
you faxed it
to us last week.
Which is why
I'm surprised
to hear you say
you have
both children
enrolled at Westcott.
Did I say Westcott?
We changed
our minds about
Westcott. It's too glitzy.
Listen, we gotta do
what's best for the
children.
Isn't that the truth?
MAN: Thank you
for waiting, Doctor. I
can take your order now.
Yes, I need five dozen
10 cc syringes fentanyl,
and I need two dozen
20 cc syringes Demerol.
We sent up
60 of fentanyl
on Monday, Doctor.
Yes, but as I noted
in the chart,
I had to double
the PC infusion rate
of Demerol in six patients.
Dr. Glass?
Deidre,
I'll be right with you.
I'm on the phone
with the pharmacy.
Dr. Wise wants to
see you in his office.
The medical director.
Wake up, Ruby.
Sleeping beauty.
All you do is sleep.
It scares me.
So you're losing
your medical license.
That's wonderful.
I have a sickness.
Yeah.
It's called self-pity.
Complicated by being born
without a freaking backbone.
So I'm weak, am I?
Maybe I am.
But at least I'm not
hopelessly greedy
and reckless,
borrowing a million dollars
from some loan sharks
and Tarzana and...
Which I would've
paid off by now!
We had a good thing going
until you stuck your hand
in the cookie jar.
A good thing?
You son of a bitch!
I was a doctor.
Yeah, but you turned
yourself into a junkie.
Not until
you did what you did.
Where were you
when I did it?
Right.
I saw an opportunity, Erin.
I saw
an opportunity,
and I grabbed it
because I had
what you didn't.
I had the nerve, the will.
Since nobody was giving me
a second chance, I just
took it.
I'm not doing this anymore.
Listen,
it's already done.
What this is about is
containing the damage,
you understand?
Good.
You know we're gonna
have to get rid of
the girl.
Speaking of which,
we're dry, aren't we?
We've got nothing
to take care of
Ruby with,
so I guess
I have to go out
and get something.
And if
I can't find
drugs in LA...
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hi.
ERIN: Wave at the camera,
Ruby. Wave at the camera.
They can't catch me.
Come in the water, Erin!
ERIN:
Wait for me!
I'm coming, too!
Okay.
Spin me, Erin! Faster!
Whoo!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Rhett.
Rhett, move away.
(SCREAMS)
Erin!
It took some doing, but
finally I found some
pharmaceutical morphine.
Erin?
God, not now.
Erin.
Erin!
RUBY: (WHISPERING)
1875 Montego Canyon.
Well, I thought
you'd want to know.
Ruby?
Honey?
Terry
needs to sit down
and talk to you kids.
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
Shh.
(SCREAMING)
You kids
are a handful,
you know that?
Where's your sister, eh?
Where's your damn sister?
(YELLING)
Let go off of me!
This is where
I should've put
you from day one.
Ah.
(ENGINE STARTING)
What's happening?
He just pulled out the Jag.
He just walked
back in the house.
Okay, just keep working.
(SNORING)
He's sleeping.
He fell asleep.
There's gonna be
a change of plans, okay?
(SNORING)
Why would he do that?
He's bombed!
He's finished off
a bottle of vodka.
Look, it's right there
on the floor.
I think I see what's
really right in front of me.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Begleiter,
what's going on?
Mr. Glass, you ought to have
your wife take a look at that.
She's not at home.
You know, I called your office
and they said that you'd be at
home.
I kept calling here
and nobody answered,
so here I am.
The bank has blocked
your guardianship account,
pending an investigation.
The trust officer,
he believes
there's malfeasance.
The sons of bitches.
Mr. Glass,
I went
out on a hell
of a limb for you.
I warned you about the
girl's claims, about
her e-mails,
about her accusations because
I trusted you and the Bakers
trusted you.
But if you've been lying,
then the courts are
going to step in,
and if these children are
taken from you, they have
no place to go.
He thought
he was helping us.
Mr. Glass,
where are the children?
At their
music lessons.
Their piano lessons.
You just watch.
Next, I'll have to
buy them a Steinway,
and the chintzy bastards
at the bank will say, "Can't
they learn to play the kazoo?"
No.
That's my Testarossa.
No, that's our Testarossa.
You see, until
we get our money back,
it's our Testarossa, Terry.
So you planned to skip town
this morning? Leave us in
a lurch, buddy boy?
That's nuts.
Where'd you get
an idea like that?
Well, your wife was
kind enough to call
us this morning,
give us a little heads-up.
My wife?
Uh-huh.
So before you leave town,
how about repaying the
entire loan
in one lump cash sum?
That son of a bitch
doesn't have our money.
What's going on, Terry?
Ask him.
Your silent partner?
Bastard robbed me blind.
Oh, my God.
I'm leaving.
No, no, no, no, no.
You're not going anywhere.
Really?
Yeah, I think
we're entitled
to an explanation.
From me?
Mmm-hmm.
I have absolutely
nothing to do
with this.
(BEGLEITER GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
Nobody listens anymore.
You happy, Terry?
Feel good about that?
Damn it, Terry,
you're a troublemaker.
I guess that took
care of the problem.
No, no, no, come on.
We're gonna discuss
this in the car. Come on.
There's nothing to discuss.
Terry,
just walk like a man
out to the Jag, all right?
That was
the whole problem,
you've dealt with it.
The rest is pure profit.
Just not the Jag, okay?
The Volvo.
Wait here for one minute,
okay?
Nice little drive in our car.
No, not in there!
No! Not in there!
I don't
even have the
keys to the damn car.
Don't sweat it, Terry,
we've got all the keys
to all the cars.
Take the Volvo,
not the Jag, huh?
Let's go! Hey, let's go!
Okay! You win,
you win, you win!
You win?
It's over, okay?
But just please
take the Volvo.
Okay?
You're making this
difficult, Terry.
Whatever.
Take the Volvo. Brand
loyalty. I like that,
Ter.
Oh, that little bitch.
You know, you're
some kind of joker.
We're gonna take the Jaguar.
No!
(GRUNTS)
(ENGINES STARTING)
Hey, you haven't been
to our Tarzana office,
have you, Mr. Glass?
We even
got a handball
court and a sauna.
And way
in the back we have
this, uh, special room.
Totally soundproof.
What the...
What the fuck!
(TRUCK HORN HONKING)
What'd you do to this car?
(SCREAMING)
Hi. You guys
need some help?
Yes.
Got everything
under control?
Yeah, we got it covered,
thanks.
Terry.
You two kids
stay in the car.
5-L-1-10, I have a
possible TC over the side.
Southbound, Malibu Canyon.
I'll be out to investigate.
WOMAN: Copy that.
5-L-1-10,
I have a rollover
TC with one fatality.
I'm gonna need two
backup units. 10-4.
(DISPATCH RESPONDING)
Ruby!
It's okay.
RHETT: Ruby, go!
Drive!
Where's the stupid key?
It's okay.
Quick, get us outta here!
Let's go!
Come on, find them!
RHETT: Ruby!
TERRY: Need your help.
He's getting closer, Ruby!
I got 'em!
He's getting closer!
(ENGINE STARTS)
Drive, drive, drive!
Why are
you stopping?
Get us outta here!
It's okay, honey!
Buckle up!
What are you doing?
It's all forgiven.
RHETT: Ruby,
what are you doing?
(SCREAMING)
You two okay? Go
back and wait by
my car.
Things will get
easier from here on.
They already have.
Let's go home.